



**UX RESEARCHER & DESIGNER** 

≥ nagel.hana@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/hananagel

hananagel.com

+1 514.245.7658



#### **EXPERIENCE**

lan, 2019 — Present

# SERVICE DESIGNER

at Element Al

Montreal

As the sole design researcher for Element's <u>flagship product</u>, I steered product development from exploratory prototype to publicly available solution.

- Gathered insights from 5 industries to inform the development of multiple AI models powering the Knowledge Scout querying platform
- Led and facilitated workshops to uncover stakeholder, end user, and client needs across diverse segments
- Bridged the technical, design, sales, and delivery paths to translate signals into actionable user interface and service design approaches, sale strategies, and solution implementation guidelines
- Developed and iterated on frameworks to rapidly identify, refine, de-risk, and build solutions with explainable Al and intuitive user flows

Sept. 2016 — Jan. 2019

# **LEAD UX RESEARCHER**

at SAP Customer Experience

Montreal

As the unit's 1st researcher, I successfully built the practice from the ground up, integrating research into the culture and product development process.

- Built UX Partner Program to gather user feedback, developed a support ticket analysis framework, and partnered with the Data Team to design an application usage dashboard
- Utilized a range of qualitative and quantitative methods to assess high impact opportunity areas and deliver design recommendations
- Maintained key relationships with technical leaders across the global organization to improve collaboration, design decisions and roadmaps
- Led company-wide initiative to scale user research practice; personally obtaining the support of the CEO and delivered report to SAP Board
- Established the first cross-company user research community (200+ members), including a Slack workspace, newsletter, and vendor demos
- Negotiated 3 global contracts for research tools and designed workshops to train employees to gather user insights

Jan. — June 2017

# **UX RESEARCHER**

at Brandfire (contract)

Remote

Provided UX research for redesign of insurance website.

- Developed journey maps, personas, and market analysis that spoke client's language and provided deep insights
- Redesigned website's information architecture (delivering site maps, task flows and process models) to address user pain points

Dec. 2015 — Sept. 2016

# **DESIGN TEAM LEAD**

at Welcome Home TO (volunteer)

▼ Toronto

Led a 12-person team on Syrian refugee resettlement project, showcased in Make Change Conference as 'inspiring maker'.

- Conducted user research and refined design solutions through participatory design and process flow modelling
- Designed high-fidelity prototypes that met strategic stakeholder requirements of industry and government partners

April 2016 — Sept. 2016

# **UX RESEARCHER**

at University of Toronto Libraries (contract)

Toronto

Provided UX support for 3rd largest library system in North America.

- Conducted usability tests and translated qualitative and quantitative findings into design improvements
  - Collaborated on website redesign for Canada's largest collection of maps and geo-spatial data

# ABOUT ME

I am a human-centered researcher and designer, specializing in agile enterprise, usability testing methodologies and digital strategy, particularly for the ecommerce and FinTech industries. A passionate advocate of evidence-based design, I focus on transforming the user experience through research, testing, and prototyping, to deliver measurable business results.

# **尽** SKILLS

#### Research

Contextual Inquiry
Task Flows
Surveys
Usability Testing
Heuristic Evaluation
Data Analysis
Information Architecture
Site Maps
Personas
User Interviews
Competitive Analysis
Accesibility Analysis
Journey Mapping

#### Design

Storyboarding
Prototyping
Wireframing
Interaction Design
User Interface
Service Design
System Design

#### Tools

UserZoom
Validately
Respondent
Optimal Workshop
SurveyMonkey
InVision
Axure
Balsamiq
Sketch
Google Analytics





**UX RESEARCHER & DESIGNER** 

≥ nagel.hana@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/hananagel

**A** 

hananagel.com

+1 514.245.7658



#### **EXPERIENCE**

April 2016 — Sept. 2016

# **UX DESIGNER**

at Nia Technologies Inc. (contract)

▼ Toronto

Provided UX consulting services for Nia, a healthcare technology non-profit.

- Prototyped features and produced service design proposal
- · Formulated insights used to design platform for clinical 3D printing
- Designed website UX and UI, and provided front-end services

January — April 2016

# **UX/UI DESIGNER**

at DECIMA (contract)

▼ Toronto

Redesigned website for GIS tool that allows historians to explore Florence.

- Increased site traffic and visitor duration through redesign website user interface, information architectire, and graphics
- Provided front-end development services to launch the website

Aug. 2014 — June 2015

#### **UX DESIGNER**

at Finabanx

Montreal

Provided UX/IA documentation for a financial technology microlender.

- · Improved product usability through research and testing
- Designed 3 application flows and dashboards for 6 websites
- · Created high-fidelity website prototypes in Axure

May 2013 — July 2014

#### **MARKETING SPECIALIST**

at Payza.com

Montreal

Worked on strategic communications for a global online payment platform.

- Increased email marketing engagement by 20% through redesigned digital communications process for a customer base of over 10 million
- Worked with product team to optimize payment platform design

May 2011 — May 2013

# DIGITAL PUBLISHING MANAGER

at FlyingBooks Ltd.

▼ Tel-Aviv

Managed product acquisition and global marketing for an iOS mobile app.

- Awarded Best New App of 2012 out of 100+ competitors
- Acquired 50+ titles and 20+ award-winning authors and illustrators
- Acted as project manager for the creation of over 70 picture books

# **EDUCATION**

Sept. 2015 — Aug. 2016

# **INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND UX DESIGN**

at Graduate Faculty of Information, University of Toronto

▼ Toronto

Sept. 2005 — May 2009

#### **BACHELOR OF ARTS, MIDDLE EASTERN STUDIES**

at Brandeis University

Boston

# DESIGN COMMUNITY

#### **Speaking**

#### **UXPA Cleveland**

Nov. 2019 | Presenter

#### **UXC HEC Montreal**

Oct. 2019 | Presenter

#### **Joint Futures**

Sept. 2019 | Presenter

# Convey UX

May 2019 | Presenter

# Web à Québec

April 2019 | Presenter

# DesignOps Summit

Nov. 2018 | Presenter

#### IoT Montreal

May 2018 | Presenter

#### Lesbians Who Tech Summit SF

March 2018 | Presenter

# Writing

How to Draw a Research
Ops Owl P.1

How to Draw a Research
Ops Owl P.2

# In the Media

High-Impact Research: The Ingredients For An Effective UX

And Design Research Practice

Forrester Research

How To Increase Your Firm's Appetite For Customer Understanding

Forrester Research

# <u>Aurelius Podcast</u>

Aurelius Lab

#### **Rosenfeld Podcast**

Rosenfeld Media

ResearchOps Spotlight: Interview with Hana Nagel

Enjoy HQ